Joanna Sijie Jiang

Technical Product Management | MVP | GTM | Roadmap | Cloud | ML | B2B | B2C | Scrum Master Certified

joannasjiang11@gmail.com | +1 (778) 680-7832

OBJECTIVE

Collaborative Technical Product Management Professional with a 4+ years background in backend engineering and strong skills in developing MVPs, writing user stories and defining product metrics.

Led 3 product features development of an end-to-end B2B/B2C integrated communication platform product that provides multiple communications services through SDK and APIs, enabling clients to build their own applications and which led to \$10 million in Annual Contract Revenue (ACR) for FY23.

STRENGTHS

Developing MVPs: Built the MVP for the B2C/B2B Integrated communication platform product by working with 3 cross-functional teams on defining high-level system design, the MVP's implementation and E2E test.

Communications: Spoke at 2018 GSA Annual Scientific Meeting Conference in Boston on the topic of longevity in healthcare space with audiences as large as 500+

Engineering Project Management: Led 2 enterprise level CPaaS projects with 3 features success launch in career

EXPERIENCE

Microsoft, Software Engineer, Cloud, IoT Communication Service, Vancouver, Canada **Achievements**

2022 - Present

- Led the software engineering aspect of 3 product features for the Azure Communication Service (ACS product), including the Customer Key Encryption product feature, which is available in 17 Geo and allowed 60K+ international financial customers to have more control over their data
- Headed general availability support for ACS Managed Identity for M.S enterprise customers globally, resulting in \$15.1M annual contract revenue (ACS main services weekly usage chat: 36,000k, message: 3,200k, SDK: 120k etc.)

Responsibilities

- Created PRDs and iterated 2 MVPs on reporting with principal level stakeholders from 3 functional areas
- Managed Engineering **Product Roadmap** by defining product features, requirements and setting scores
- Organized scrum meetings with cross-functional teams to prioritize product engineering backlog, define task, and drive progress
- Conducted 10 enterprise customer interviews and studied market trends to understand and converted pain points to actionable engineering-facing user stories
- Collaborated with other product teams across 3 different time zones to deliver advanced virtual visit feature, that provides >1,000 attendees onboarding at the same time and leads to a customers retention rate increased by 3%
- Led cross-functional E2E development of credential management feature resulting in engagement of +17% users
- Implemented ACS product features via full-stack development and E2E test using C#, JavaScript, React and .NET

Ames IT, Software Engineer, Project Management, Los Angeles, CA

2020 - 2021

Achievements

• Led the API integration of the first virtual telemedicine platform product in the senior center in collaboration with Microsoft increasing the user's onboarding time of health consultation completion by 30%

Responsibilities

 Conducted Voice of Customer Interviews and designed customer surveys to visualize gap between customer's expectations and needs

- Identified and drove functionality, performance **requirements**, and **user story** for a senior center virtual consultation platform to provide real time care service in the convenience of 1000+ seniors
- **Defined** product's technical **KPI** including latency, availability, reliability and recoverability

Keck School of Medicine (USC), Research Assistant, Los Angeles, CA

2018 - 2019

- Achievements: published 2 papers in biomedical field
- Implemented decision tree algorithm (ML) for NIH funded research to analyze and predict factors influence slow-wave sleep and daytime neuropsychological performance in the elderly based on 3TB clinical data
- Collaborated with data analyst to validate model using 20% of dataset and performed model evaluation via ROC and AUC

EDUCATION

University of Southern California	2019
Master of Science in Statistics and Gerontology	Los Angeles, CA

The George Washington University	2016
Bachelor of Science in Management Information System	Washington, D.C

EDUCATION

Scrum Master Certified (SMC)	2020
Scrum Alliance, Credential ID 001048809	Los Angeles, CA

SKILLS

Product Management Skills: Technical Product R&D, Team Leadership, GTM, QA Testing, SaaS Solutions, Requirement Gathering & Analysis, Market & Competitor Research, Test-Driven Development, Jira, Agile,

Technologies and Tools: C#, Java, Python, JavaScript, .Net, React, Sql, SDLC, Tableau, DevOps